A Guide to the Rose Terry Cooke Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6651
Rose Terry Cooke Collection 1866-1891
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6651
11 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit, 1961 Oct 24
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - "Home at Last", 1881 Sep 20; AMsS, 2 p.
    [Poem]
  - "The Red-Winged Goose", n.d.; AMsS, 22 p.
    [With author's corrections.]
  - "Old Cool", n.d.; AMsS, 17 p.
    [Includes printed biographical sketch of Rose Terry Cooke from "Literature, a Weekly Magazine."]
  - "The Death of Goody Nurse: A Ballad of Salem", n.d.; AMsS, 7 p.
    [Poem.]
- Letters
  - Rose Terry Cooke to James Thomas Fields, 1866 Feb 27; ALS, 1 p.
    [Covering letter for manuscript sent to the
    Atlantic
    mentions earlier manuscript sent to Fields; discusses improving health and a book underway.]
  - Rose Terry Cooke to Editor, Youth's Companion, 1879 Apr 19; ALS, 1 p.
    [Expresses pleasure of manuscript acceptance; mentions ill health.]
  - Rose Terry Cooke to [James Ripley] Osgood, 1881 Mar 10; ALS, 3 p.
    [Discusses reviews of her books, her novel not yet done, health, and pleasure at spring's arrival.]
  - Rose Terry Cooke to Editor, Traveller, 1882 Nov 19; ALS, 1 p.
    [Discusses her policy of requesting payment on receipt for Christmas story.]
  - Rose Terry Cooke to Mrs. Perkins, 1885 Nov 10; ALS, 1 p.
    [Response to a reader wishing directions for finding a particular story.]
  - Rose Terry Cooke to [Henry Chandler] Bowen, 1887 Oct 4; ALS, 2 p.
    [Writes from her new home in Pittsfield, Mass.; says she is ill and preparing a story for the
    Independent
    . ]
  - Rose Terry Cooke to Edward William Bok, 1891 Jan 9; ANS, 1 p.
    [Covering note for "fifty words" he had requested.]